Guide to the Maung Maung Gyi papers, 1953-1986
Maung Maung Gyi papers, 1953-1986
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Maung Maung Gyi papers, 1953-1986.
4421
Maung Maung Gyi.
1 cubic ft.
Notes, clippings, manuscripts, periodicals, speeches, and articles.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files relating to the Burmese historical, cultural, political, and economic situation. There are drafts of typescript articles and handwritten notes, several Burmese newspapers, clippings, manuscripts, journals and periodicals. The journal Forward contains General Ne Win's speeches and articles about modernization projects, politics, foreign relations, the economy, agriculture, and medical care. The Burma Association Newsletters and The Burma Bulletin, published in the United States, deal with issues of interest to the Burmese people in regard to their homeland, such as the account of the December 11, 1974 massacre of students, monks, and other citizens over former United Nations Secretary-General U Thant's burial site; human rights, political issues, folk tales, and other timely articles are also included.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Maung Maung Gyi is a professor at Bates College.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files relating to the Burmese historical, cultural, political, and economic situation. There are drafts of typescript articles and handwritten notes, several Burmese newspapers, clippings, manuscripts, journals and periodicals. The journal Forward contains General Ne Win's speeches and articles about modernization projects, politics, foreign relations, the economy, agriculture, and medical care. The Burma Association Newsletters and The Burma Bulletin, published in the United States, deal with issues of interest to the Burmese people in regard to their homeland, such as the account of the December 11, 1974 massacre of students, monks, and other citizens over former United Nations Secretary-General U Thant's burial site; human rights, political issues, folk tales, and other timely articles are also included.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Maung Maung Gyi.; Ne Van, U, 1911-
Places:
Burma--Politics and government--1948-
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- The University of Chicago Roundtable. "Meanings of Democracy.", Sept. 27, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Perspective of Burma." An Atlantic Monthly supplement., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Handbook of Burma published during World War II, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Asian Survey, Vol. 4, Nos. 3, 6., Mar. 1964, June 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Forward Periodicals., 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newspaper clippings., 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- One paper: "Entourage and Circle in Burma," by L.M. Hanks ( The Bennington Review)., ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- One brochure: Address by General Ne Win, Chairman of the Burma Socialist Party at the opening session of the Fourth Party Seminar., Nov. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Three booklets: Asia Research Bulletin, 1972, Columbia Books on Asian Studies, 1976, and Social and Economic Studies, Dec. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Typescript and manuscript notes for various articles., 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Notes for the translation of Kinwan Mingyi's diaries., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Yale University Library, Southeast Asia Collection. Burmese Accessions List., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Notes on the history of Burma, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Typescript draft and manuscript notes for an article entitled, "Constitution-making, Burmese Socialist Style.", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Typescript draft and manuscript notes for an articles entitled, "The Burmese Military Junta's Quest for Legitimacy.", ca. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The Burma Association Newsletters., 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Periodicals printed in the Burmese language., 1971-ca. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Accounts of the massacre in Rangoon on December 11, 1974 of university students and other citizens by the military government under the leadership of General Ne Win., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Burma Studies Group News., Nov. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Typescript draft and manuscript notes for a paper entitled, "Nation Building, Politics and Power: A Case Study of Burma.", ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- A preface and introduction for a book--no title given. Typescript copy., ca. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- The Burma Bulletin., Jan. 1975-Apr. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- One article: "Is There a Burmese Nation?", ca. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- One photocopied Burmese manuscript (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Burmese newspapers., 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "Burma: A Selective Guide to Scholarly Resources.", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Typescript notes for Politics, Power and Political Culture., ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Handwritten notes and typescript manuscript for article, "Why Ne Win?", ca. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Various short articles re: culture, history, government and people of Burma. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- One plastic box containing 3"x5" cards with manuscript notes., 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)